Guide to the Cornell University International Agriculture records, 1952-1980.
Cornell University International Agriculture records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University International Agriculture records, 1952-1980.
21-2-1700
Cornell University.International Agriculture.
46.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Maps/Charts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes terminal reports, research papers, proposals, maps, general correspondence, progress reports, photographs, and other records of the University of the Philippines-Cornell Graduate Education Program.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes terminal reports, research papers, proposals, maps, general correspondence, progress reports, photographs, and other records of the University of the Philippines-Cornell Graduate Education Program, which Cornell later developed into International Agriculture. Records relate to agricultural planning and research, plant breeding, plant pathology, soil science, animal husbandry, agricultural economics, various agricultural education and exchange programs, and related topics.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; University of the Philippines-Cornell Graduate Education Program.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Agriculture--Philippines.; Agriculture--Economic aspects.; Plant-breeding.; Plant diseases.; Animal culture.; Soil science.
Places:
Philippines.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. UPCA Participants
Box 1-2
Series II. Cornell University Participants Administration
Box 2
Series III. Project Leaders
Box 2-3
Series IV. Professors
Box 3-4
Series V. Consultants
Box 4
Series VI. Graduate Students
Box 4-5
Series VII. Interviews on UPCO by K.L. Turk
Box 5
Series VIII. Terminal Reports - Alphabetical List
Box 6
Series IX. Volumes
Box 12, 14 and 18
Series X. Sound Recordings
Box 15
Series XI. Photographs
Box 13 and 15
Series XII. SEARCA, SEAMES and University of the Philippines
Box 15
Series XIII. University of the Philippines - Cornell University Graduate Education Program(UP-Cornell) - Chronological File
Boxes 7-11, 15, 17, 25-47
Series XIV. University of the Philippines - Departmental Files
Boxes 16
Series XV. Alphabetical File
Boxes 19-24
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. UPCA Participants
  - Ag1ibut, Andres P, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anonuevo, M. G., 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Umali, D. L., 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Orillo, F. T., 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bernardo, F.A., 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Saguiguit,G.F. and Reyes, E.D., 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Romulo, C.P., 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Castillo, L.S., 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Castillo, Gelia T., 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - de Padua, D.B., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Flores, T.G., 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lantican, R.M., 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Villanueva, L.J., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yniguez, A.D., 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Barril, C.R., 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Corpuz, I.T., 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Deanon Jr., J.R., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - del Rosario, E.J., 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - de Vera, M.R, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dosayla, E.D., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fernandez, W.L., 1966-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Gagni, A.O., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Javier, E.Q., 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Juliano, C.P., 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Labadan, M.M., 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mamicpic, N.G., 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Melgar, J.V., 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Momongan, V.G., 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miranda, Dulce, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Miranda, Senen, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Necesito, A.C., 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ona, P.A., 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rimando, L.C., 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Rosario, E.L., 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Sajise, P.E., 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Talisayon, S.D., 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - UPCO Fellowships (short-term), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bautista, O.K., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Deomampo, N.R., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - de la Paz, S.P., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gregorio, L.B., 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Legaspi, E.C., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lu, H.Y., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mendoza, E.R., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mercado Jr., A.C., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ables, H.A., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Baradas, M.W., 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bautista, S.R., 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Covar, P.R., 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lozada, R.B., 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rivera, S.C., 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - UPCA General, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - C.U. Business Office re: Philippine Project, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II. Cornell University Participants Administration
  - Palm, C.E., 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Peterson, A.H., 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series III. Project Leaders
  - Bradfield, Richard, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Brady, N.C., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Everett, H.L. to Turk, K.L., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Turk, K.L. to Everett, H.L., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Everett, H.L. to Zuidema, L.W., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Trimberger, G.W. to Turk, K.L., 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24-29)
  - Turk, K.L. to Trimberger, G.W., 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - Trimberger, G.W. to Zuidema, L.W., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - Metz, J.F. to Turk, K.L., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Turk, K.L. to Metz, J.F., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Metz, J.F. to Zuidema, L.W., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Vittum, M.T. to Turk, K.L., 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6-12)
  - Turk, K.L. to Vittum, M.T., 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Vittum - Newsletters, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Oyer, E.B. to Turk, K.L., 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Turk, K.L. to Oyer, E.B., 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Professors
  - Ainslie, H.R., 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Barker, Randolph, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Bond, M.C., 1963-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Bouldin, D.R., 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Bourne, M.C., 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Cushman, H.R., 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Darrah, L.B., 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Durfee, A.E., 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Feuer, Reeshon, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Glass, E.H., 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hathcock, J.N., 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Herrington, B.L., 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Knott, J.E., 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Levine, Gilbert, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miller, J.C., 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Munger, H.M., 1963-1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Musgrave, R.B., 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Pederson, C.S., 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Schultz, O.E., 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sentz, J.C., 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Smock, R.M., 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Steinkraus, K.H., 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Strength, D.R., 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Tom, F.K.T., 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Uhler, L.D., 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Wallace, D.H., 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Young, R.G., 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Series V. Consultants
  - Blackwell, Sara, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Canoyer, H.G., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Crowder, L.V., 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gandelman, Hiram, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hand, D.B., 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Kennedy, W.K., 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Kent, G.C., 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Korf, R.P., 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Loosli, J.K., 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Pimentel, David, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Plaisted, R.L., 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Powell, Whiton, 1963-1970 (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
  - Schmidt, G.H., 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Scott, M.L., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Thurston, H.D., 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Travis, B.V., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Walsh, R.L., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Ward, W.B., 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wood, M.B., 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Series VI. Graduate Students
  - Dumont, K.P., 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Dutcher, R.D., 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Early, Alan C., 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Francis, C.A., 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fujimoto, Isao, 1963-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Grant, R.J., 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Heichel, G.H., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Johnson, W.L., 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Kampen, Jacob, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Koppel, B.M., 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Magdoff, F.R., 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Maurer, A.J., 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Novak, J.R., 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Nyberg, A.J., 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Palmer, A.F.E., 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Philipson, W.R., 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pickett, D.R., 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Robertson, C.A., 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sanchez, P.A., 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Voth, D.E., 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Wheelock, G.C., 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Wickham, T.H., 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Wien, H.C., 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Zehr, E.I., 1965-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Final Planning Sessions for UPCO Program, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Fund Raising Consultant, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Status of ICA-NEC Participants, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Ford Review Team Report, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - List of Theses, Publications, etc. from UPCO Program, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Series VII. Interviews on UPCO by K.L. Turk
  - Bernardo, F.A. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Drilon, J.D. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Javier, E.Q. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Labadan, M.M. (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Lantican, D.M. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Lantican, R.M. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Orillo, F.T. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Oyer, E.B. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Saguiguit, G.H. (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Sandoval, Pedro (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Umali, D.L. (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Wickham, T.H. (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Memorandum of Understanding, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Renewal of Memorandum of Understanding, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Ford Grants, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Ford Grant, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Ford Grant, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Ford Grant, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Policies re: UPCO Program, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Series VIII. Terminal Reports - Alphabetical List
  - Ainslie, Harry R., 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Barker, Randolf, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Blackwell, Sara, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bond, Maurice, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bouldin, David R., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bourne, Malcom C., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Crowder, Loy V., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Crowder, Loy V., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cushman, Harold R., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Darrah, Lawrence B., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dumont, Kent P., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Durfee, Arthur E., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Dutcher, Roger D., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Early, Alan C., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Feuer, Reeshon, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Francis, Charles A., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Fujimoto, Isao, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Gandelman, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Glass, Edward H., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Grant, Robert J., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hand, David B., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Hathcock, John N., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Heichel, Gary H., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Herrington, B.L., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Johnson, William L., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Kampen, Jacob, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Kennedy, W.K., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Kent, George C., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Knott, James E., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Koppel, Bruce M., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Korf, Richard P., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Levine, Gilbert, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Levine, Gilbert, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Loosli, J.K., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Maurer, Arthur J., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Miller, James C., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Munger, Henry M., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Munger, Henry M., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Musgrove, Robert B., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Novak, Joseph R., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Nyberg, Albert J., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Oyer, Edwin B., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Palmer, A.F.E., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Pederson, Carl, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Philipson, Warren, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Pickett, Douglas R., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Pimental, David, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Plaisted, Robert L., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Powell, Whiton, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Powell, Whiton, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Powell, Whiton, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Robertson, Charles A., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Sanchez, Pedro A., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Schmidt, Glenn, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Schultz, Otto E., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Scott, Milton L., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Scott, Milton L., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Sentz, James C., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Smock, Robert M., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Steinkraus, Keith H., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Strength, Ralph, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Thurston, H. David, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Tom, Frederick K.T., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Travis, Bernard V., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Uhler, Lowell D., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Voth, Donald E., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Wallace, Donald H., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Walsh, Robert L., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Wang, Thomas S.C., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Ward, William B., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Wheelock, Gerald A., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Wickham, Thomas H., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Wien, Hans Christian, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Young, Robert G., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Zehr, Eldon I., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Ad Hoc Committee, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Castillo, Leopold S., Corpuz, Imidio T., Miranda, Senen M., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Borril, Carlito R., Fernandez, William L., Lantican, Ricardo M., Melgar, Jesus V., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Deanon Jr., Jose R., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - del Rosario, Ernesto J., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Musgrave, Robert B.(consultant), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Series IX. Volumes
  - University of the Philippines - Cornell University Graduate Education Program(UP-Cornell)
    - Progress Report of the UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program: For its First Two Months of Operation, November 1, 1963 (Box 12, Volume 1)
    - Progress Report of the UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program: For its Second Two Months of Operation, January 3, 1964 (Box 12, Volume 2)
    - Report on the University of the Philippines College of Agriculture (UPCA) Development Program, August 1964-June 1966 (Box 12, Volume 3)
    - My First Year in the Philippines, 1964-1965: A Report to the Project Leader, May 30, 1965 (Box 12, Volume 4)
    - Report of the UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program for Its First Year of Operation, June 30, 1964 (Box 12, Volume 5)
    - Annual Report of the Ford Sponsored UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Volume 6-14)
    - Nine Years of Ford of Ford Foundation Supported UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program, 1963-1972: Terminal Report of Cornell's Activities, August, 1973 (Box 12, Volume 15)
    - Report of the Consultant in Library, March 23, 1967 (Box 12, Volume 16)
    - International Communication: A Report by Thomas G. Flores, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Volume 17)
    - List of Theses, Publications, and Other Educational Materials Resulting from the UP-Cornell Graduate Education Program, April, 1971 (Box 12, Volume 18)
    - An Integrated Research Program Proposal on Production, Processing, and the Utilization of High Protein Foods, January, 1970 (Box 12, Volume 19)
    - Possibilities of Improving Santa Cruz Soft Cheese, 1970 (Box 12, Volume 20)
      Best Research Paper Award in Animal Science (First Prize, 1970)
    - An Evaluation of Mass Selection and Family Selection for Corn Improvement in a Tropical Environment, March, 1969 (Box 12, Volume 21)
      PhD Thesis by Hakim, Rusli M.
    - A Development Program for the College of Agriculture University of the Philippines, July, 1962 (Box 12, Volume 22)
      A Report of a Special Review Team of the Ford and Rockefeller Foundations and Cornell University
    - Preliminary Report: UPCA Staff Housing Project, January 7, 1963 (Box 12, Volume 23)
      Oversize
    - Final Report on the Assistance Between the U.S. Agency for International Development, the State University of New York and the University of the Philippines College of Forestry, July, 1966 (Box 12, Volume 24)
    - Architectural Blueprints for Staff Housing, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Oversize and includes a furniture brochure
    - Annual Report of the College of Agriculture, 1961-1974 (Box 14, Volume 1-13)
      Annual Report of the Dean of the College of Agriculture to the President of the University of the Philippines
      Missing Annual Report from 1971
    - Plan for the Establishment a Department of Food and Technology in the UPCA, February 5, 1964 (Box 14, Volume 14)
    - Report of the Consultant and the Committee on the Improvement of the Cafeteria and Dormitory Management, April 29, 1964 (Box 14, Volume 15)
    - And So They Stay On, November 4, 1964 (Box 14, Volume 16)
      Case Studies Based on Interviews with Key UPCA Personnel
    - Guidelines on the Effectiveness of an Agricultural Institution, July 15, 1965 (Box 14, Volume 17)
    - Committee Report: Ad Hoc Self-Study Committee for the Los Banos Unit, April 1, 1969 (Box 14, Volume 18)
    - Directions, Designs for Decisions in the Seventies, April 29, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 19)
    - Departmental Introspections and Projections for the Seventies, July, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 20)
    - UP at Los Banos: Development Goals and Plans for the Seventies, September 21, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 21)
    - Proceedings of the Symposium in Search of a Breakthrough in Agricultural Development, December 9-10, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 22)
      Includes the Program for the Symposium
    - The Philippine Agricultural Research System: Evaluation and Recommendations, December 20, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 23)
    - Recommended Research Areas for Philippine Agriculture in the Seventies, December 20, 1971 (Box 14, Volume 24)
  - South East Asian Ministers of Education Secretariat (SEAMES) and Southeast Asian Regional Center for Graduate Study and Research in Agriculture(SEARCA)
    - Final Report South East Asian Ministers of Education Secretariat (SEAMES) Second Conference, November 25-28, 1966 (Box 18, Volume 1)
    - Final Report First Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for the Southeast Asian Regional Center for Graduate Study and Research in Agriculture (SEARCA), June 20-22, 1967 (Box 18, Volume 2)
    - Final Report Second Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for the SEARCA, October 25-27-1967 (Box 18, Volume 3)
    - Final Report Third Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, May 23-24, 1968 (Box 18, Volume 4)
    - Final Report Fourth Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, November 5-7, 1968 (Box 18, Volume 5)
    - Final Report Fifth Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, May 21-23, 1969 (Box 18, Volume 6)
    - Final Report Sixth Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, September 11-12, 1969 (Box 18, Volume 7)
    - Final Report Seventh Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, April 2-3,1970 (Box 18, Volume 8)
    - Final Report Eighth Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, October 20-24, 1970 (Box 18, Volume 9)
    - Final Report Ninth Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, May 4-8, 1971 (Box 18, Volume 10)
    - Final Report Tenth (Special) Meeting of the Agricultural Advisory Council for SEARCA, August 23-24, 1971 (Box 18, Volume 11)
    - Summary: Project Blueprint - SEARCA (Box 18, Volume 12)
    - Updated Project Blueprint: SEARCA, August 31, 1968 (Box 18, Volume 13)
    - National Seminars Report SEARCA, August 11-25, 1967 (Box 18, Volume 14)
    - Regional Seminar Report SEARCA, September 27-29, 1967 (Box 18, Volume 15)
    - Seminar Proceedings SEARCA, February 7-10, 1972 (Box 18, Volume 16)
    - Annual Reports SEARCA, 1968-1973 (Box 18, Volume 17-23)
      1968 and 1969 prepared by the Interim Regional Center Offices. 1970-1973 Prepared by the Regional Center Office in the Philippines. 1972 Report includes both Part A and Part B.
- Series X. Sound Recordings
  - Dr. Javier and Dr. Lantican, tr-9331 (Box 15)
    90 minute Cassette Tape
  - Dr. Orillo, tr-9332 (Box 15)
  - P.R. Sandova, Mario Labadan, R.M. Lantican, tr-9333 (Box 15)
  - E.B. Oyer, tr-9334 (Box 15)
  - J. Drilon, Sandaval, tr-9335 (Box 15)
  - Tom Wickham, Dean Umali, tr-9336 (Box 15)
  - Dr. F.A. Bernardo, Dr. Saguiguit, tr-9337 (Box 15)
- Series XI. Photographs
  - Harrar, Hill, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bourne UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Levine UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Munger UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Musgrave UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Strength UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Young UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Wien - Graduate Assistant UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University Graduate Assistants UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Philippino UPCO Participants, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Cornell University Professors at UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Dean and Mrs Umali - Visit to Cornell, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Dean and Mrs Orillo - Visit to Cornell, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Samonte - Visit to Cornell, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - UPCO Photographs, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - IRRI, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Sec. Freeman and Ambassador Williams at UPCO, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Photo Album, 1952-1962 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - UPCA Photos, 1952-1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - UPCA Photos Continued, 1952-1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Series XII. SEARCA, SEAMES and University of the Philippines
  - Draft Report of the Task Force Report on a SEAMES Graduate Study Research Institute, September 23, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - UPCA and SEARCA Bulletins, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Social Laboratory - UPCA/SEARCA, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series XIII. University of the Philippines - Cornell University Graduate Education Program(UP-Cornell) - Chronological File
  - Cornell - UPCA Contract, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Cornell - UPCA Contract Continued, 1954-1960 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Guidelines for UP-Cornell Staff, 1952-1966 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - "Rebirth of a Ghost College" Report and Photo Album, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Operations Administration(FOA): Mission to the Philippines, 1955-1958 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Consists mainly of FOA bulletins and typewritten memorandums of articles from mainstream newspapers about the program
  - Special Reports on the Agriculture of the Philippines and the Far East, 1955-1959 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - News clippings, 1956-1973 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Dean D.J. Umali Visit to Cornell, May-July, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - UPCA Reports and Expenditures, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Personnel and Financial Policies, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - UP-Cornell Staffing Pattern, 1963-1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Talk by Dean Charles Palm at UPCA, November 6, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Polson Reports, January, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 18)